LONG NGUYEN

Rochester, NY (willing to relocate) • ngkhlong189@gmail.com • 309-631-4516 • Linkedin • Portfolio

TECHNICAL CAPABILITIES

Tools: Programming Language: Python (numpy, pandas, matplotlib, scikit-learn), SQL (DDL, DML), R (tidyverse, dplyr, ggplot2, caret); Data Visualization: Tableau, Power BI, Excel; Cloud: AWS (S3, Redshift); Big Data Technology: Spark, Databricks Skills: Statistical Analysis, Predictive Modeling, Machine Learning (Clustering, Classification, Regression), Data Modeling

SELECTED PROJECTS

Data Analytics: Behavioral Segmentation for a hotel and resort company

Built a K-means clustering model in Python on a hotel and resort dataset of > 80k customers to segment them into different behavioral groups, and provided key strategies to enhance customer experience and maximize revenue for each segment.

Machine learning: Mental health classification (Python) | Alternative implementation in R with statistical analysis

Deployed 5 predictive models in Python to determine whether a tech employee sought mental health treatment, with SVM attaining a leading F1 score of 75% and an accuracy of 74.6%.

Data Engineering: NYC bike tracking forecast

Led a team of four in developing an end-to-end ETL pipeline, employing PySpark to create bronze, silver, and gold data tables; Achieved a 70% accuracy rate in building a forecasting model using Prophet for the Citibike Bike Sharing app on Databricks.

Data visualization: Visualization of layoffs across industries

Created an interactive dashboard with descriptive statistics and a world map showcasing layoffs across industries in **Tableau**.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UNIVERSITY OF ROCHESTER

Rochester, NY

Teaching Assistant

Aug 2023 - Dec 2023

- Mentored students in diverse statistical areas: descriptive statistics, probability and distribution, confidence intervals, hypothesis testing, inference, ANOVA, and regression analysis.
- Led 10 review sessions for exams and projects, resulting in an 80% increase in students' overall grades.
- Empowered students in understanding R packages and creating impactful reports with RMarkdown.

REL8ED.TO ANALYTICS

Rochester, NY

Data Science Intern

Jul 2023 - Aug 2023

- Led an end-to-end project to classify >100K N.A companies into industries with 85% accuracy using Python and OpenAI's embedding model, saving over \$500K in manual processes and paving the way for future LLM implementations.
- Developed an automated scraper for 10M companies' homepage data using Python, stored in JSON format, collaborating with the software team to create a seamless API, resulting in a substantial 90% reduction in data retrieval time.
- Built 6 comprehensive sales performance dashboards using Tableau, resulting in a 15% increase in revenue for the clients.

LEAFPRINT ENTERPRISES

Cedar Hills, UT

Data Analyst Intern

- Jan 2022 May 2022 Developed intricate dictionaries and efficient data models using SQL for World Archive's geographical data, contributing to a
- Created detailed documentation for Python scripts and SQL queries, facilitating smoother collaboration and enabling seamless project understanding, ultimately leading to a 40% reduction in onboarding time for new team members.

BENIT PTY LTD

Hanoi. Vietnam

Data Analyst Intern

Mar 2021 - Jul 2021

- Built ML models on historical data of > 1M users using Python to segment users into different behavioral groups, and predict user lifetime value, enabling better product strategies, user engagement, and acquisition plans.
- Led 2 company-wide analytics projects in cross-app user behaviors, subscription optimization, and ad revenue prediction, contributing to an increase in user engagement by 10%, and ad revenue by 15%.
- Designed and analyzed 5 A/B tests, assisting product managers in making data-driven decisions on product improvement and revenue optimization.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF ROCHESTER

Rochester, NY

STEM Master of Science in Data Science - GPA: 3.63/4.0 **AUGUSTANA COLLEGE**

Winter 2023

Rock Island, IL

Bachelor of Arts in Applied Mathematics - GPA: 3.77/4.0

30% enhancement in data organization efficiency.

Summer 2022